# Christopher. Obando

**■** chrisjobando@gatech.edu

chrisjobando.com

**(706)** 414-4232

in chrisiobando

O chrisjobando

### SUMMARY.

I am a third-year Computer Science major at the Georgia Institute of Technology. I have three years of experience in software development in React, Java, and Python. Self-taught web and mobile application developer accustomed to working in fast-paced Agile development cycles. Passionate about accessibility-driven design and social good.

### SKILLS.

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT.

Java

Python

Command Line

Git

C/C++

Bitbucket

VersionOne

Jenkins

**MATLAB** 

#### APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT.

React

NextJS

TypeScript

React Native

JavaScript

BabylonJS

NodeJS

Express

MongoDB

SASS

Angular

HTML

CSS

### **DESIGN TOOLS.**

Sketch

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

**POV Ray** 

Blender

Autodesk Maya

#### LANGUAGES.

Native Spanish

### MISCELLANEOUS.

Community Service

Foster Care

Video Production

Cinematography

Adobe Premiere

Adobe After Effects

Guitar

### EDUCATION.

#### **GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science 2020

Minor in Film and Media Studies

Major Concentration: Media and People Thread

#### CODEPATH Sept. 2019 to Dec. 2019

Android Development Bootcamp

#### UNIVERSIDAD CARLOS III DE MADRID

International Exchange

### WORK EXPERIENCE.

### **REDFIN** · Software Engineering Intern

Seattle, WA · May 2020 to Aug. 2020

- Upcoming internship with the Customer Relationship team
- Front-end development of customer service tools in ReactJS
- Direct interaction with agents and home-buyers

#### **ELAVON INC.** · Software Engineering Intern

Atlanta, GA · Aug. 2019 to Dec. 2019

- Reduced security threats detected through Fortify Security Software by implementing safer coding solutions in Java.
- Worked in a diverse Agile/Scrum team of developers and QA engineers on the Elavon Bridge application.
- Designed JUnit5 test cases to detect bugs and fix them.
- Presented all development changes during daily Standup meetings and biweekly Sprint Review meetings.

## **GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY** · Computational Services Intern

Atlanta, GA · Feb. 2018 to Dec. 2018

- Operated under the Office of Information Technology for the Ivan Allen College of Liberal Arts and DILAC VR Lab.
- Provided technical support for professors and students in three separate buildings on campus.
- Diagnosed issues with machines and was dispatched to fix both software and hardware issues.

### PROJECTS.

#### NONPROFIT PORTAL Sept. 2019 to Present

- Collaborated with a team of developers, a project manager, and a designer to streamline the application process for the Bits of Good club at Georgia Tech.
- $\bullet \ \mathsf{Reduced} \ \mathsf{screening} \ \mathsf{time} \ \mathsf{for} \ \mathsf{nonprofits} \ \mathsf{to} \ \mathsf{partner} \ \mathsf{with} \ \mathsf{Bits} \ \mathsf{of} \ \mathsf{Good} \ \mathsf{to} \ \mathsf{pair} \ \mathsf{them} \ \mathsf{with} \ \mathsf{student} \ \mathsf{developers}.$
- Gained an understanding of the full MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, and Node.js) and Next.js.

### FINDIT Oct. 2019

- $\bullet$  Lead Front-End Development and UI/UX Design for HackGT 2019 submission
- Created an application in React Native that allows for lookup of nearby stores/restaurants and allows the user to generate a QR code order
- Intended for those with language barriers or hearing disabilities to order at nearby merchants in-person
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Worked on merchant-side web QR reader application (built with ReactJS and NextJS) that reads and displays the order depending on their QR entry) } \\$

# SPOTIFY WEB APPLICATION

Feb. 2019 to Apr. 2019

June 2017 to Present

Jan. 2019 to June 2019

- Showcased an understanding of React framework, working with the Spotify API, and User Interface Design skills.
- Launched a responsive application that serves as a media player, profile insights tool, song recommendation generator, and recently played history log.

### UNEAT CAFETERIA ORDERING APPLICATION

- Apr. 2019 to May 2019
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Cooperated in a team of five to develop an application that allowed students to order food from the school cafeteria.}$
- Programmed in Angular, TypeScript, and SASS to develop an Ionic App.
- Managed user and order data using the Firebase platform.

### LEADERSHIP + ACTIVITIES.

### $\textbf{GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY} \cdot \textit{Teaching Assistant (CS2261)}$

Jan. 2020 to Present

Dec. 2019 to Present

- Gained teaching experience through weekly recitation lectures
- $\bullet \ \text{Integrated a needed automated grading system using the Canvas API and shell scripts}\\$
- Enabled students in the course to succeed through personalized teaching methods, holding office hours, and being aware of external academic and emotional resources available for students

### BITS OF GOOD · Director of Community

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Planning internal community events, such as socials, mixers, and member retreats}\\$
- Leading committee meetings to create and uphold traditions
- Building alumni network
- Serving as public relations for the organization

### BITS OF GOOD · Lead Front-End Developer

Aug. 2019 to Present

- Working in an agile development cycle to create a nonprofit portal for organizations to connect with Bits of Good
- Programming client-side web application in React/Redux.
- $\bullet \ \ Coordination \ with \ the \ lead \ designer \ to \ implement \ their \ vision \ for \ the \ portal's \ user \ interface.$

### OTHER CAMPUS INVOLVEMENTS

Society of Hispanic Professional Engineers, Hispanic Recruitment Team, Filmmakers @ GT, Theta Chi Fraternity, HackGT, Well-Being Activators, Interfraternity Council, Musicians Network, Freshman Servant Leadership Organization